https://www.universalclass.com/myinterests/privacypolicy.htm

Privacy Policy
Click here to view our Cookie Policy.
Universal Class, Inc. takes your
privacy seriously. Please feel free to review our
Privacy Policy:
Because we want to provide you with
the most efficient, enhanced, and secured service, we may request information
about you. This Privacy Policy outlines your privacy rights for using
UniversalClass service and lets you know how we ("UniversalClass") collect, use, store and otherwise share information you have provided
us in order to use our services.
This Privacy Policy in conjunction
with our Terms of service as well as any other agreements or policies provided
by UniversalClass governs your use of our services.
If you do not agree with this
Privacy Policy, our Terms of Service, or any other agreements or policy that
governs use of our service, you should not use any of our services.
About this Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy covers our treatment of personally
identifiable information that we collect when you are anywhere on our sites,
and when you use any of our services.
This policy does not apply to the practices of
companies, schools, or other organizations that we not own or control, or
to people that we do not manage or employ. UniversalClass contains several
links to other sites and we are not responsible for the privacy practices
or the content of those sites.
Summary of Information We Collect and Track
General Usage Information. UniversalClass collects information about all users
collectively, such as what areas users visit and what services members
use. This data is automatically retrieved. This type of general
information is not used to identify specific users, but in an aggregate
form to help us analyze traffic patterns and enhance our service to better
serve our users and advertisers.
UniversalClass Member Registration. When you register on any site or service provided by
UniversalClass, we ask for personal information from you such as a
username, first name, last name, email address, password, country and
other related information. This information is required in order to
provide a course to you as well as secure and store your course progress
and potential course completion. When you log in to our services with your
username and password (that identifies your registration data), you are
not anonymous to us. Both General Usage Information and any personal
details you provide to us is used to enhance and customize content,
identify (and in some cases validate) you when you post or share content,
participate in a class, or access any of our member-privileged services.
Creating, Joining, Taking, or Using our Virtual
Classroom Environment. When you
create, join, take, or use our Virtual Classroom Environment, you are not
anonymous to us, the instructor(s) within the class, or the student(s)
within the class you have enrolled. Personally and identifiable
information about you such as your UniversalClass username, your first and
last name, and your email address is made available to our staff,
instructors, proctors and other course facilitators in order to both help
and assess your course progress. This information is used to better
enhance your online education experience and to promote free and open
inquiry as well as to hold class participants personally responsible for
their work and behavior within the online class. You do have the option of
sharing your course work and other identifiable information about yourself
to fellow course participants. Should you choose to do this, we are not
responsible of how fellow class participants decide to use this
information about you.
Information We Collect Using
Automated Processes
When you access any part of our
service, including browsing our website, reviewing articles, and/or reviewing
our course catalog and course listings, we collect technical information through
automated means. This information may include without limitation:
Technical information about the
device or computer you’re using to access our services, such as date/time of
visit, device type, your IP address, operating system information, browser,
browser language, information accessed, and other systems information; and
Usage statistics about your
interaction with our services, including pages visited, courses accessed, time
spent on pages or the services, pages visited, search queries, click data,
portions of the services used, date and time, and other information regarding your
use of the services.
This collected data through automated
means may also be linked to your information and is provided using server log
files and tracking technologies. The primary data collection technologies UniversalClass
uses are as follows:
Cookies. A "cookie" is a
small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it
can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser
remember some specific information and to help maintain "state". A
cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other
websites. We may use cookies to help identify you when you visit our site. All
of our member-privileged services require the use of cookies. While you may opt
to disable cookies on your browser, our service will not work correctly or at
all.
Web beacons. A web beacon is a small
object that allows us to determine what actions visitors of our service perform
when using our service.
Server logs. When you make a request for something hosted on our service (directly or indirectly),
such activity is logged. This logging includes technical information, such as the date/time
of request, your IP address, page/item accessed, your computer type, browser type, and other
technical information.
A Note About Cookies
UniversalClass
and other third-party data collection tools such as Google Analytics (and/or
other third party advertisers) may use scripts, server logs, cookies, web beacons
or other data collection tools when you access or use any of our services. We
may correlate this information gathered by these means to other
information about you as described in this Privacy Policy.
We may use
web beacons or other data collection technologies in order for us to determine
if a specific page or service was opened, accessed, or activated and/or to
determine what promotions to offer a user.
We use
cookies in order to allow you to login to our service, improve the
functionality of our service, collect and analyze usage of our service so we
can improve it, provide a personalized experience of our service, prevent fraud
and abuse on our service, customize your experience of our service, and help
provide a more efficient delivery of our service.
For
example, UniversalClass may use cookies for any of the following reasons:
Essential cookies. These cookies are essential for our website to function.
These cookies secure your credentials when you log in to our service. They also
help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to fight abuse and fraud.
Statistics and Measurement cookies. These cookies allow us to count visitors, visits, pages viewed, etc. They help us improve how our website functions.
Tracking/targeting cookies. These cookies record your visits, links followed, and pages viewed. We use this information to make the site relevant to your interests.
Security.
We use cookies to secure your credentials when you log in to our service. These
cookies help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to
fight abuse and fraud.
Customization.
We use cookies to customize your experience of our service by remembering your
preferences on how our service looks and behaves to fit your individual
preferences.
Maintain
State. We use session cookies to maintain your current state (in order to
determine if you are currently logged in) and be able to show you purchases
made, courses you are currently taking or have completed, and provide
account-specific information.
You may
set your browser to disable cookies from a website. You will need to review
your specific browser documentation regarding how to disable cookies. If you do
disable cookies from our service, then our service will not work properly, and
you will not be able to access member-specific services, such as taking
courses.
By using
any of our services, you consent to the use of cookies, web beacons and any
other data collection tools we may use as described in this Privacy Policy.
Third Party Analytics Tracking
UniversalClass uses the following third-party tracking services on our service:
Google Analytics. This service may use data collection technologies such as
cookies and web beacons. These analytics services help us determine how users
interact and use our service and/or how users found our service (for example, by
clicking on various ads or other website links that connect to our website). This
information collected on our behalf by these third-party analytics services
help us improve our services as well as to understand how people use our services.
UniversalClass uses Google to
measure the performance of its advertising. To measure advertising performance,
Google uses small strings of text (known as cookies) that are placed on your
computer when you click on our ads. Cookies typically remain active on your
computer for about 30 days. If you visit certain pages of the UniversalClass's
website during that period, Google and UniversalClass will be able to tell that
you saw the ad delivered by Google. If you'd like to know more about how Google
handles information gathered from the use of cookies, please read their privacy policy. You
may opt out of Google Analytics by downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out
Browser Add-on.
UniversalClass may use third-party
advertising technologies to deliver marketing information and advertisements
about our services to you on other websites or online applications. These ads
may be tailored to your interests based on the content of a page you visited,
searches you may have conducted, various demographic information provided by
server logs and/or web beacons, and/or activity you may have done over time
across different websites.
We use third parties advertising and
analytic services (such as advertising networks and advertising servers including
but not limited to Google Analytics, DoubleClick and others) to help deliver
these tailored advertisements on other websites and online applications. These third-party
advertising services may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your
computer or other online-enabled. These third-party advertising services may
access these cookies that they have placed on your device or use other tracking technologies
in order to serve these advertisements.
We do not have access to nor does
our Privacy Policy govern the use of cookies or other tracking technologies
that may be placed on your computer or device from these non-affiliated,
third-party entities. Third
parties that use these technologies may offer you a way of opting out of advertising
tracking and targeting. For example, to opt out of Google Analytics for display
advertising or customize Google display network ads, you may visit the Google
Ads Settings page. We
do not control any of the third-party advertising services and companies and we
have no control over whether any company chooses to participate in advertising opt-out
programs.
What
We Do with Collected Data
UniversalClass may use information
we collect for the following reasons:
General statistics, traffic analysis, and site usage.
Order fulfillment. We require personal
information such as full name, email, address and other details in order to
verify online payments and fulfill orders and subscription purchases. Data
collected from UniversalClass members (people who have filled out our
registration form and logged in) is used to identify the member in order to
allow that member to join and participate in our online classes.
Course progress and course
completion. We use collected information in order to track your course
progress, assessments, and course completions.
Communications. We use collected
information to facilitate communication between you and instructors, course facilitators,
staff, and other students.
Security. We use collected information
to both identify you and secure your account.
Account preferences. We use
collected information to allow you set your account preferences.
Provide support. We use collected
information in order to provide customers with support and resolve issues.
Analyze usage and traffic. We use collected
information in order to analyze service usage and traffic.
Advertise. We may used collected
information to advertise additional products and services.
Prevent abuse. We use collected information
to identify and prevent fraud and abuse of our service.
Customize service. We use collected
information to customize various parts of our service.
Sharing
of Information We Collect
UniversalClass will share your
information that we have collected (such as registration information, coursework,
and/or course progress/completion information) with the following third-parties:
Instructors
and Course Facilitators:
Your account information that we have collected will
be shared with course instructors and course facilitators so that they can
properly assess your course progress and answer any course-related questions.
Business
Partners, Contractors and/or Agents:
UniversalClass may hire or partner with other
companies to perform certain functions and in these instances, we may share your information with these third-party companies.
For example, we may hire third-party companies for payment processing, order
fulfillment, marketing services, data analysis, hosting services, and support.
UniversalClass may partner with other
organizations and/or business to train their patrons or employees. When we partner
with another company to perform these functions, we may provide collected
information to the partner showing how their employees or patrons are using the
service. If you are accessing UniversalClass service through a business partner
(such as a library or through your employer), this Privacy Policy does not
govern their use of your Information; you will need to review their Privacy
Policy in these cases.
Other
UniversalClass Members:
If you engage in sending/accepting
contacts, email other course participants, post to the Class discussion forums,
opt to share any course completion awards, and/or set your profile to be viewable
by the public, then this information may be accessible to the general public.
Additionally, if you ask a question or send a comment to an instructor or
course facilitator, information such as your full name may be publicly viewable
by others. UniversalClass is not responsible for information you choose to make
public on its web sites, and if you do not want this information to be public,
select to use this service "privately" in the "Account Settings" area or the "Privacy Settings" area. It is equally
important to note that if you choose to use our Virtual Classroom Environment
(by either creating, teaching, joining, or using one or any of our online
classes) some personally identifiable information is released about you to
class participants. This information is limited to your first and last name
(the name you entered when you signed up on UniversalClass), email address, and
your UniversalClass username and any other information you decide to share to
the public.
Business Transfers:
Although unlikely, UniversalClass may sell its businesses
or assets. In transactions such as these, customer information is generally one
of the transferred business assets. Should UniversalClass or one of its
business lines be sold, customer information may be one of the transferred
assets.
Your Permission:
We may share information with third parties outside
the scope of this Privacy Policy if you have specifically authorized us to do
so.
Non-disclosure of Your Personal Data
We will not sell, share, or
otherwise distribute your Personal Data to third parties except as provided in
this Privacy Policy. We may disclose your Personal Data to other Universal
Class affiliates worldwide that agree to treat it in accordance with this
Privacy Policy. Personal Data may also be transferred to third parties who act
for or on our behalf, for further processing in accordance with the purpose(s)
for which the data were originally collected or may otherwise be lawfully
processed, such as services delivery, evaluating the usefulness of this
website, marketing, data management and/or technical support. These third
parties have contracted with UniversalClass to only use Personal Data for the
agreed upon purposes, and not to sell your Personal Information to third
parties, and not to disclose it to third parties except as may be required by
law, as permitted by us or as stated in this Privacy Policy.
Personal Data collected from you may
also be transferred to a third party in the event that the company and the
customer data connected with it is sold or transferred, in which case we would
require the buyer or transferee to treat any Personal Data in accordance with
this Privacy Policy.
Personal Data may also be disclosed
to a third party if required by applicable law, court order, or government
regulation, or if such disclosure is otherwise necessary in support of any
criminal or other legal investigation or proceeding.
Security of Information We Collect
We work hard to protect the security
of your information during transmission by using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)
software, which encrypts any sensitive or financial information you submit. It
is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and
to your computer. Be sure to log off when finished using a shared computer.
Selecting a Public Profile
If you decide to create or update
your profile to be "public" then your areas of interest,
course completions, your full name, and any other information you may have submitted
about yourself will be made public to UniversalClass members, as well as the
Internet, and as well as the general public. By making your profile
"public" you completely accept that personal information about
yourself is no longer made private and you are no longer considered
"anonymous". UniversalClass is not responsible for how others may use
information you set to be public.
Our Commitment to Children's Privacy
Protecting the privacy of the very young is extremely important to us.
For this reason, we do not collect or maintain information at our website from anyone who
identifies themselves as being under the age of 13 in the U.S. or under 16 in the European Economic Area.
UniversalClass is an adult service for adult learners.
If you have knowledge of someone using our service under the age of 13 in the U.S. or under the age of 16 in the European Economic Area,
please contact us at privacyhelp@universalclass.com so we can take steps to remove the account and associated information.
How You Can Access or Correct Your
Information
If you have registered on the
UniversalClass service, you have access to your
personally identifiable information. You can update or correct this information
under "My UniversalClass" by clicking on the link "Edit Profile". Your profile is unique and secured by your Universal
Class Username and Password.
Removing Your Account
If you would like to remove your
account and registration information from our service, you may do so by logging
into “My Classes”, selecting the menu item “Account Settings” and pressing the
button “Account Removal”. Follow the procedures outlined there to verify and
complete your account removal request.
If you are having issues with
removing your account on our service, please contact your helpdesk directly for
help: https://www.universalclass.com/helpdesk
Please note that removing your account
does not remove any content you may have posted, comments you may have sent,
submissions you may have made, or emails you may have sent. Removing your
account does not remove any information that you may have been posted or sent
through a Third-Party Platform (such as Facebook). Even after your account has
been deleted (or terminated), we may retain your information for as long as we
have a legitimate purpose to do so and in accordance with applicable law in
order to assist with any legal obligations, prevent fraud and abuse, enforce
our agreements and policies, and/or resolve disputes.
Release of Student Records
Once you have completed an online
course, your student records are available for up to 7 years from the date of
completion in the form of an online certificate (if you purchased the
certificate option), and available under the "My Transcripts" area.
You personally control and are responsible for any release of this information
to other parties. You can set whether or not your certificate is available to
other people using the 'Share My Award' feature located on the online version
of your certificate. For example, you can select whether or not it is private
(viewable only by you) or public (viewable to anyone) and/or whether it is
password protected (viewable only to people who have the password).
Our Commitment to Data Security
UniversalClass.com has taken several
security measures in order to protect the information under our control. All
personal information we collect is stored on machines owned by UniversalClass,
Inc. at a secured location in order to ensure that no unauthorized individuals
have access to the equipment or its data.
Option to Discontinue Direct
Communications
If you would like to discontinue
communications with our company, simply submit your request to our online
helpdesk: https://www.universalclass.com/helpdesk -- please include your name, email address registered on
the site, and username along with the removal request. Removal requests are
usually processed within 1-2 business days.
If You Reside Outside the United States
Universal Class, Inc. is a U.S. company and its headquarters are located in Florida. In order for Universal Class, Inc. to provide any services to you, your data must be transferred and processed within the United States. By visiting any of our websites or using any of our services, you consent to the storage of your data on servers that are located within the United States. If you are using using any of our services from outside the United States, you agree to the transfer, storage, and processing of your data in the United States (or other countries). Specifically, personal data collected in Switzerland and the European Economic Area (EEA) is transferred and stored outside of those areas. By submitting your data (filling out a web form, registering for a course, making payments, etc.) or by using any part of our services, you agree to this transfer, storage, and processing of your data that may be outside your country.
How to Contact Us
Universal Class, Inc. is committed
to protecting your privacy. If you have any questions regarding our privacy
policy, please contact privacyhelp@universalclass.com.
UniversalClass Cookie Policy
A Note About Cookies
A "cookie" is a small piece of information sent by a web server to store on a web browser so it can later be read back from that browser. This is useful for having the browser remember some specific information and to help maintain "state". For example, we may use cookies to help identify you when you visit our site. All our member-privileged services require the use of cookies. While you may opt to disable cookies on your browser, our service will not work correctly or at all.
UniversalClass and other third-party data collection tools such as Google Analytics (and other third party advertisers) may use scripts, server logs, cookies, web beacons or other data collection tools when you access or use any of our services. We may correlate this information gathered by these means to other information about you as described in our Privacy Policy. For example, we may use web beacons or other data collection technologies in order for us to determine if a specific page or service was opened, accessed, or activated and/or to determine what promotions to offer a user.
Why Does UniversalClass Use Cookies and Other Data Collection Technologies?
We use cookies in order to allow you to login to our service, improve the functionality of our service, collect and analyze usage of our service so we can improve it, provide a personalized experience of our service, prevent fraud and abuse on our service, customize your experience of our service, and help provide a more efficient delivery of our service.
For example, UniversalClass may use cookies for any of the following reasons:
General statistics, traffic analysis, and site usage.
Security. We use cookies to secure your credentials when you log in to our service. These cookies help protect your account against unauthorized access and helps to fight abuse and fraud or any activity that violates our terms and agreements.
Customization. We use cookies to customize your experience of our service by remembering your preferences on how our service looks and behaves to fit your individual preferences.
Maintain State. We use session cookies to maintain your current state (in order to determine if you are currently logged in) and be able to show you purchases made, courses you are currently taking or have completed, and provide account-specific information.
You may set your browser to disable cookies from a website. You will need to review your specific browser documentation regarding how to disable cookies. If you do disable cookies from our service, then our service will not work properly, and you will not be able to access member-specific services, such as taking courses.
By using any of our services, you consent to the use of cookies, web beacons and any other data collection tools we may use as described in our Privacy Policy.
Your Cookie Opt-Out Choices
To opt-out of Google Analytics or Google Advertising, please contact Google directly: Google Opt-Out.
If you'd like to delete cookies or instruct your web browser to delete or refuse cookies, please visit the help section of your web browser.
Please note that disabling cookies will remove your ability
to take any courses and will cause the website to not function correctly.
Additional Help
If you have any additional questions regarding our use of cookies, you may contact us at privacyhelp@universalclass.com.
© 2020 Universal Class, Inc.
Privacy Policy
Terms of Service
